<books>
    <book ID="HDBrownie_Louse Book" Title="Arthropodae Qudiae, Volume XXVI">
        <page>
When one speaks of the louse, one tends to imagine a pest that either presents little to no nuisance or, if one were a mammal, asks relatively very little of its host -- some blood here, some secretions there, both of which are in plentiful supply. Were one to speak ill of the louse, it would be in tones of irritation and not of hushed fear.

If one were to speak to other insects about them, one would perhaps gain some appreciation for their plight. It is not as if the lice {{W|*chose*}} to develop into parasites, after all. Would it not be possible to both deny them purchase on one's flesh and to forgive them for needing it?

Not if one were a fish. Indeed, I have spoken to various fish who felt rather strongly about the little devils. The species that prefer fish hosts tend to be rather more invasive than the ones that feed on mammals, either latching on for dear life or even riding inside of them. The befoliaged among us should feel at least a little sympathy at the thought of a louse infestation -- after all, they are not so dissimilar to the rampant horrors that are aphids.

All of that said, there are two particular species of note, both seemingly peculiar to Qud, that are rather more dangerous than your everyday louse.
        </page>
        <page>
I will begin with the lesser horror, the drink louse, also referred to at times as the "live and drink" louse. It is a solitary creature and, like its cousins, sustains itself on blood.

However, the drink louse is unable to extract blood itself! Its mandibles are simply not up to the task. Why does it have them in the first place, you may ask? I have never had the heart to ask it; it does not need its pitiful existence rubbed in its face.

Instead, the drink louse will find blood spattered on the floor -- it is a surprisingly common resource, where faction relationships have risen to a boil -- and simply remain there drinking it, day after day, until the blood is all gone.

But this is not the truest hallmark of nor the most interesting thing about the drink louse. Indeed, the tendency from which it receives its name is that of identifying live beings who are transporting liquids, and hitching a ride with them. It will stow away in a choice waterskin and do as it does with blood, supping on it day after day until there is none left to sustain it.

Despite preferring blood, the drink louse's appetite is surprisingly versatile -- I have yet to discover a single liquid which it will {{W|*not*}} consume, if it is held by a higher being. Occasionally, this works against the poor louse -- it is unable to digest acid fast enough to counteract its corrosive effects, and thus will attempt to drink the liquid and subsequently perish.

There is one more feature worth noting about the drink louse. Although it is perfectly content to feed from waterskins, if given the opportunity, it will take up roost inside the mouth of any being with a tongue and the capacity to drink. Naturally, it excises the tongue so as to make room, as its lesser cousins do to fish. Thenceforth, it will share meals and water with its host.

No doubt the loud, panicking ape reading this, who now knows a fraction of the fear which a fish may feel about lice, will wish to know how the louse can be removed once it has taken root. Never fear -- you need but either contract glotrot, causing the louse to voluntarily detach, or consume acid until it dies.
        </page>
        <page>
TODO
        </page>
    </book>
</books>
